PETER HELLWEGE

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER & DATA ENGINEER

- phellwege1@gmail.com
- https://peters-portfolio.net/
- **(**208) 697-3323
- in peter-hellwege/
- n phellwege

With over 8 years of experience in delivering software, providing financial advice, sales, and exceptional customer service, I am dedicated to utilizing my passion for technology to develop innovative solutions that positively impact people's lives. I bring strong skills in communication, relationship management, and technical expertise to collaborate with like-minded teams and make a valuable contribution to any organization.

Skills

LANGUAGES

JavaScript(ES6), JAVA, Python, CSS

FRONT END

React, Angular

DATABASES

SQL (MySQL, SQLite), NoSQL (MongoDB), OracleSql, Spark, Firebase

CODE EDITORS

Visual Studio Code, SpringToolSuite4, Oracle SQL developer, JetBrains, PowerBi

OTHER

Azure Dev Ops, Azure Data Factory, Azure Data Bricks, AWS, Git, Postman, Mongoose, Django ORM

Employment

Allata Eagle, ID Senior Consultant 2021 to Current

Currently contracted to Vizient Inc., a Fortune 100 company, as a Data Engineer, performing advanced SQL querying, designing data pipelines with Azure Data Factory, and cleansing data with Databricks. Developing critical business reports and delivering them to executive stakeholders. Committed to providing excellent software engineering services, including building internally facing interfaces using Angular and ReactJS to enhance data accessibility.

Washington Federal Bank

Boise, ID 2020 to 2021

Director of Service

As the Director of Services for Washington Federal Bank, I managed a high volume of customer interactions with an average of 70-120 clients per day. In this fast-paced environment, I demonstrated my exceptional multitasking skills and consistently delivered quality customer service. My ability to build great client relationships while providing solutions to their banking needs helped to establish my reputation as a trusted and reliable professional.

Epic Realty

Eagle, ID 2019 to 2020

Real Estate Consultant

In my role as a Real Estate Agent at Epic Realty, I successfully navigated complex financial transactions and effectively negotiated contracts. My unwavering commitment to delivering trusted advice and exceptional service helped me to establish a reputation as a reliable and knowledgeable professional within the industry. Through my strategic approach to sales and contract management, I helped my clients to achieve their desired outcomes, building lasting relationships along the way.

Kendall Auto Group

Nampa, ID 2017 to 2019

Sales Consultant

Provided expert sales and customer service. Exceeded all sales metrics monthly while building meaningful long term relationships with clients and coworkers alike.

Projects

Space Tourism

Space Tourism is a multi-page front end challenge. It's mobile friendly down to 375px wide and functions by indexing a JSON file.

- Solo project, designing and implementing code architecture, chasing a wireframe from frontendmentor.io
- Dynamic and responsive site. Cleanly build from the ground up while following the wireframe.

Rock-Paper-Scissors

Rock-Paper-Scissors is a simple game that keeps track of your score through state management. I designed the architecture to be as smooth as possible without the need for any page changes.

- Solo project, designing and implementing code architecture, chasing a wireframe from frontendmentor.io
- A true single page application designed to be efficient and fast.
- \bullet Testament of my state management, and following ReactJS's life cycle.

Star Wars Homecoming

Text based Star Wars game built from scratch, written in Python, Django, and SQLite, with a lightweight backend.

- Collaborated on a team of three and coordinated planning, creating wireframes, and group discussions in order to increase overall productivity on the project, and delivered within a 4 day time frame.
- Designed a responsive, clean front-end interface using CSS, and JQuery to create a more seamless user environment. Integrated and implemented a lightweight SQLite database using Django.
- Optimized security, and user data by integrating Bcrypt. Validated code using W3 Code Validator to ensure it functioned at its maximum potential.

TipCalculator

Tip Calculator Front end project built out with html, CSS, and JavaScript.

- This was a solo project, designing and implementing code architecture, chasing a wireframe from frontendmentor.io
- Quickly iterated a functional product that matched the wireframe, and created a mobile friendly version.
- Tested thoroughly before deploying with GitHub pages.

Education

Coding Dojo

Cert Full-Stack Developer Certification 2021

Immersive Full-Stack Training Program in Python, Java and MERN